export const chapter = "Chapter - 6: Janapadas to Mahajanapadas ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What marked the emergence of janapadas in ancient India around 600 BC?",
        optionA: "The construction of towns",
        optionB: "The establishment of a republic",
        optionC: "The invention of writing",
        correctAnswer: "The construction of towns",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ancient literature is a chief source of information for the period 600 BC-400 BC in India?",
        optionA: "The Ramayana",
        optionB: "Buddhist and Jain literature",
        optionC: "The Mahabharata",
        correctAnswer: "Buddhist and Jain literature",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the common practice used to expand territories in ancient India?",
        optionA: "Building forts",
        optionB: "Conducting Ashwamedha Yajna",
        optionC: "Negotiating with neighboring rulers",
        correctAnswer: "Conducting Ashwamedha Yajna",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How were rulers chosen in some republic janapadas in ancient India?",
        optionA: "By heredity",
        optionB: "By popular vote",
        optionC: "By the oldest member of the council",
        correctAnswer: "By popular vote",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following was a prominent confederacy of republics in ancient India?",
        optionA: "Kuru",
        optionB: "Vatsa",
        optionC: "Vajji",
        correctAnswer: "Vajji",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What marked the transition from janapadas to mahajanapadas in ancient India?",
        optionA: "The spread of Buddhism",
        optionB: "The establishment of a republic",
        optionC: "The emergence of more powerful states",
        correctAnswer: "The emergence of more powerful states",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What did the king appoint to advise him in the administration of the territory?",
        optionA: "Senators",
        optionB: "Ministers called amatyas",
        optionC: "Village headmen",
        correctAnswer: "Ministers called amatyas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How were taxes primarily collected in ancient Indian janapadas and mahajanapadas?",
        optionA: "In the form of cash",
        optionB: "In the form of food grains",
        optionC: "In the form of precious metals",
        correctAnswer: "In the form of food grains",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What caused the Vedic varna system to become rigid and birth-based?",
        optionA: "Inter-caste marriages",
        optionB: "The influence of Buddhism",
        optionC: "The evolution of jatis (castes)",
        correctAnswer: "The evolution of jatis (castes)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which religious movements, influenced by the growing gap between Brahmins and common people, emerged in ancient India?",
        optionA: "Hinduism and Zoroastrianism",
        optionB: "Buddhism and Jainism",
        optionC: "Sikhism and Islam",
        correctAnswer: "Buddhism and Jainism",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Many towns developed into janapadas as new territories were added to them. Thus, the janapadas were newly-formed ___________.",
        options: ["Cities", "States", "Republics"],
        correctAnswer: "States",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A common practice in those times to expand territories was to conduct the Ashwamedha Yajna. When a ruler grew powerful, he conducted it. In it, a horse was released, and the territory it traversed was considered his. This practice was used to ___________ territories.",
        options: ["Establish", "Expand", "Protect"],
        correctAnswer: "Expand",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Some janapadas were ruled by kings; they were not elected or chosen by people, rather they became kings by heredity; that is, the eldest son of a king became the king. In a monarchy, all power was centered with the king. This type of rule is known as a ___________.",
        options: ["Republic", "Democracy", "Monarchy"],
        correctAnswer: "Monarchy",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The process of expansion of the territories continued. Now, one janapada wanted to occupy another, and with this, four major janapadas emerged. These powerful janapadas came to be called mahajanapadas, ruled by kings. Name one of the four major janapadas that emerged into mahajanapadas: ___________.",
        options: ["Vatsa", "Democracy", "Republic"],
        correctAnswer: "Vatsa",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The king was considered to be equal to God and appointed a council of advisors or ministers called amatyas to help govern the territory. Among the important amatyas were: purohit (the spiritual head and chief advisor), senani (army commander), and sangrahitri (treasurer). This council of advisors played a crucial role in the ___________.",
        options: ["Tax collection", "Administration", "Religious rituals"],
        correctAnswer: "Administration",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The taxes levied by the king could be in the form of cash, kind, or services. As most people were farmers, agriculture was the most important source of tax. It was one-sixth of the produce and was payable in the form of ___________.",
        options: ["Precious metals", "Food grains", "Cattle"],
        correctAnswer: "Food grains",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Vedic varna system evolved into a close system where occupations became jatis (castes) based on birth. This rigid system put restrictions on intermarriage and intermixing. What was the result of this rigid system?",
        options: [
          "Social harmony",
          "Economic growth",
          "Restrictions on intermarriage and intermixing",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Restrictions on intermarriage and intermixing",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Different towns were linked with roads, and river-ports and seaports were built for trade by ships. Traders and craft persons formed guilds called shrenis, which helped in controlling the price, distribution, and quality of the manufactured goods. These guilds were instrumental in regulating ___________.",
        options: [
          "Religious rituals",
          "Trade and craft industries",
          "Tax collection",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Trade and craft industries",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Brahmins dominated society in religious matters by helping people perform yajna and other rituals. The rituals became elaborate and expensive, creating a gap between the Brahmins and common people. This gap led to the growth of ___________.",
        options: ["Democracy", "Buddhism and Jainism", "Monarchy"],
        correctAnswer: "Buddhism and Jainism",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Now, the coinage became common, and the barter system became extinct. Punch-marked copper and silver coins began to be used as money. Weights were standardized and were measured in multiples of ___________.",
        options: ["Five", "Ten", "Sixteen"],
        correctAnswer: "Sixteen",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The Sahara Desert is the largest hot desert on the planet.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Most of Saudi Arabia is covered by lush rainforests.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The varna system in ancient India evolved into a more open and flexible system.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Buddhism and Jainism grew as a result of a widening gap between the Brahmins and common people in India.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Ashwamedha Yajna was a common practice for conducting trade in ancient India.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "The capital of Saudi Arabia is Jeddah.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mahajanapadas in ancient India were ruled by elected councils.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The traditional nomadic people of Saudi Arabia are known as Bedouins.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Trade in ancient India was primarily conducted by ships in river-ports and seaports.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The birth-based caste system in India allowed for social mobility and intermarriage between castes.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
